Welcome all to this tutorial.
Today I'm making an addition to the course
and there has been a lot of demands for a lot of different things.
I will keep on adding them as time keeps passing by.
This is a progressive course
so the content just keeps getting added as long as there is demand for it.
Now in this particular edition, I have decided to teach you more about keyloggers.
So here I will show you how you can make a keylogger, which will record key strokes elsewhere
and then later on, we will get into the deployment techniques for a keylogger
I already demonstrated some of the deployment techniques in the previous tutorials
that are general purpose
but these things will be very specific to a keylogger
even though they can easily be adapted to other malicious pieces of code.
Anyway, address here is is the fact that we will start to do some really advanced things here
here and you're going to probably
encounter a lot of errors
a lot of problems along the way so
that's natural especially because we're
moving into more advanced stuff and
merely because you yourselves are doing
to be making a keylogger several things
to take into consideration so several
prerequisites that we need to keep in
mind and before I gone any further let
me just say that we're not going to
actually do anything technical in this
tutorial urologists talk about what we
will need what will our setup be and for
what environment is this particular
keylogger meant for so I have decided to
create a keylogger for a Windows PC so
it doesn't matter that much
which version of Windows are you running
so it can be pretty much he 781
even ten you have it doesn't really
matter but we will be creating a
keylogger 40 Windows PC why have I
decided to create a keylogger that will
work on Windows well let's face it most
of the desktop users will be using
windows and deploying a keylogger on a
Windows or Mac is significantly more
difficult so we might get into that
later on
indeed course but for the time being I
will show you I want to show you how you
can meet a keylogger that will get you
can in fact a Windows PC with so here
are some of the things that we will need
first of all we will need a virtual
machine off windows I know that there
are a lot of Mac users that are
attending a course you don't have to buy
windows or anything of the kind you can
score to the Microsoft website you do
need to register and then you can get
one to three month trial period three
months is more than you really need some
90 days is really need to finish this up
to finish this to follow through this
tutorial I am NOT encouraging piracy or
anything like that but because you can
get like an IUD free trial so there is
no need to download from the torrents or
anything of a kind of get cracked
versions on Torrance I wouldn't
recommend them why I really don't know
what somebody has embedded into those
systems somebody could have altered them
to serve a malicious purpose when you
sold the monitor system or something of
a kind
therefore I really really really would
recommend doing that and there really
isn't any need you can just go over to
the Microsoft website register and
download pretty much any Windows you
would like a recommended be at least
seven and shouldn't really download
anything below seven I mean people still
use some people still use four-star a
lot of people still use XP contrary to
popular belief that it's extinguished
that its extinct
but I wouldn't recommend downloading
data systems just go ahead and download
7 and above though if you can get 8.1
and you can it's free you can get a free
Windows itself is not free for you would
have to pay for a permanent license bird
for a trial period
anybody can download and evaluate anyway
I have also opted not to demonstrate how
you can download windows and install
Aditya VirtualBox why
well all you need to do is go to be
Windows web site to a Microsoft Windows
web site and download from there pretty
simple if you encounter any problems or
difficulties there just let me know I
will design tutorial specifically for
dad I can do that quite fast played on
there is a need
pretty much most of the student pool
windows so you already installed at once
ideas and how to do it by now if you
don't it's ok just let me know in the
discussions in European or something of
a kind and I will create an additional
story award at the procedure for
installation which in VirtualBox is
exactly the same as for any other system
the dust that we have installed as far
into virtual box there is literally no
difference just downloaded and installed
to virtual box like before so all these
things are already short for other
operating systems they were there are no
significant differences for Windows it's
pretty much the same but as I said you
find it very difficult to reach
challenging just let me know and I will
do a specific demonstration here when
watching that I would like to address
before I continue on that is not really
related to the subject is the discussion
section and the private messages so I
would advise everybody who is pushing
destroyed by this point of time if you
came this far radical to post your
questions in the public discussions so
if a solution is found your problem for
malicious all that everybody can see it
regardless of that if you send me a PMI
will help you
either way so whether it's a PMR with it
and public discussions I will help you
either way so no worries there but if
you could it would be very nice if you
could please all your problems in the
discussion section where they are
visible to an accessible by all also
there are a lot of discussions again on
average 25 increase in 12 hours that's a
lot if I by some chance miss one or
something like that
go ahead and send you p.m. and a link to
their discussions hehe my problem and I
will address it immediately I am really
sorry I generally don't you to save
have answered like 95% of the question
so dear but there are 25 percent always
that I'm missing somewhere in the fridge
or these one percent that perhaps on the
table saw were something of a kind but
as I said if you don't get an answer
within 12 or 24 up to 24 hours usually
eaten within 12 you don't get it up to
24 just send a private message and I
will address your problem immediately
anyway so before we go into next
tutorial I would advise you to install I
would advise you to install a virtual
machine of Windows if you already have
Windows running a physical machine there
is no strict requirement that you should
install of you then it's recommended you
do it
gonna be running a lot of code and India
later tutorials will also be running
some destructive code that you on your
main system and instead you want mister
p.m. and you can reinstall it easily if
you can't fix the problem so that's it
as far as that is concerned now on to
the requirements so as I said neither
windows continuing with the requirements
actually do windows aside from that will
need to go ahead and download an IDE
integrated development environment a
place where we will do the code where we
will do
coating we will create our own key
logger and aside from that rule Sony
Decompiler something to actually compile
the code to create to create machine
create something that a machine can
understand from what we taken from what
we use the user can understand and that
would be it's obviously windows I D and
pilot those three things we're going to
need for an idea I have chosen to use
Eclipse I will show you how to install
it set up in all of that later dorial
but it will have some requirements so
you will need to download e you will
need to download stuff from Java which I
will also show and demonstrate no
worries there but it's all free so you
won't need to pay for anything is there
no way no additional costs at all the
programming language that I have chosen
to use is C++ code for Windows is
written in C++ on top of that C++ has
the lowest amount dependencies for
example if you are going to run each
other code you need any job opening in
the backgrounds of somebody doesn't have
a Java Runtime Environment as it is
called running under Windows PCs Java
code will not work Java is also a
programming language like C++ is a
programming language if you some other
programming languages like Python again
on Windows you're gonna have a lot of
dependencies are pretty much whatever
you use aside from ABC sharp and C++ and
C you will have a condo defenses which
you're going to need to worry about
because you do not know what is
installed on somebody else's EC you need
to create something that will
universally work on pretty much all the
PCs that are running the Windows
environment regardless of what they have
installed on your PC with India
operating system that is why that is one
of the main reasons why actors and C++
and usually hacking code and stuff like
that idea scripting language for
something simple or complex work like a
keylogger
its C or C++ example if you used ceded
nearly in the Linux demean as Linux is
mostly written in C when it says anyway
C++ can be can be tedious can be
difficult can it syntax can be complex
and don't give up immediately just
follow the tutorial tutorials I want
skip any steps I will show you how it is
done one step at a time with no steps
skipped and you will be able to see each
line of the code as you make it then
each line of the code will be explained
so you will have an understanding of it
before we can actually get into writing
a keylogger we will set up the
environment and eight unique to first of
all introduce you to some basic things
about C++ so I will introduce you to see
the basic things there and then we
wanted more advanced things through the
process of creating agree keylogger so
learned by doing however I would also
advise you to use external material you
have a lot of videos on C++ subject on
youtube so if you expand your knowledge
there and take a look at some additional
things you have the discussions don't
necessarily need to ask if you have a
problem if you don't understand
something go ahead and ask I'll be happy
to help you out in any way I can
anyway that is what is waiting for us
here so you will learn how to make a
keylogger ourselves and hopefully you'll
be able to modify it any way you like
this longer will be talking to be a
professional one or something like that
but it will be able to serve the purpose
that we needed to serve furthermore
writing custom code as opposed to just
under three key logger from the net does
have tremendous advantages primarily
because antivirus detection one of the
waste of within her selection is to rate
custom code as simple as possible and
have it for yourself and there's nobody
else has a 10 the security companies
that weekend hours program
know about it and even though they have
some general detection methods they will
not have any dick specific detection
methods for your piece of code so keep
that in mind if you wud of August on the
net
especially their closed source you have
no idea what you're done duty I mean
even if you buy one again the company ok
city around with such things but you
still have no idea what you are down
there you have to be really really
really careful with that on the other
hand if you make yourselves you know
exactly what is in there you know
exactly what it does you have for
understanding of it and a lot of people
have asked me to show you as a lot of
advanced stuff a lot of advanced things
and I decided to begin with Dad first
tutorial from this the series of the
series of advanced been testing let's
put it so will be how to make your own
key logger and then later on we will go
into some other interests
more interesting stuff so to see however
until next tutorial I bid you farewell
and I wish you a ton of luck with this