Welcome all to this tutorial.
Today we will go ahead and set up the needed environment in order to be able to code in C++
and in the final account of things, make a keylogger.
So while I was doing the testing, I had encountered into a lot of problems
and I have managed to solve them.
If anybody's wondering, I am not a magician.
I don't just go encounter problems and then just the type a few things and solve them immediately.
I do what everybody else does.
I go ahead and browse the web and try to figure things out where the problem lies.
That is exactly what I did here
and I will show you what you need to do and where the problems will occur.
Anyway, so the first thing you will need is a IDE
so an integrated development environment
and for that I have chosen to install Eclipse, which is fantastic.
However its java-based and if a
java-based we will need something from
drama but will get that's really gotten
tape in the lips pressed enter it says
mars eclipse oK so that's just the
latest version you have
lunar eclipse marks mars eclipse I like
the Cal per click that I used for those
are just the danes for the versions just
like you have war for example Linux
distributions they can hold various
names I can't think of any at the moment
but for example you have Debian Weezy or
did you just see something of a kind for
experimental things and so on and so
anyway you get the idea the area that's
completely irrelevant mars eclipses just
a name for it thats mars released that
just the name for it again that's all
there is to it so anyway what would you
like to do
well we would like to download it so go
ahead and click on Download it's
completely free or you don't need to pay
for anything and let scrolled downward
it says eclipse IDE for Java developers
plugin in Eclipse for PHP this is the
one that we're looking for a solar
eclipse IDE for C C++ developers you
have an option here for Windows of
course you can change your target
environment here but we are downloading
the one for Windows you can also use it
to Linux it's also on Linux cell accused
UT creator for C++ in particular for
pretty much everything else eclipse is
also so let's go ahead and select here I
have a 64 bit system running I don't
know which sort of a system do you have
a 64 bit go ahead and download 32 bit
that's pretty much all you need to do
just check something really fast
need
their ago so you can just go ahead and
click on this PC or on my computer if
its return my computer discarding click
on Properties and you will be given this
problem here or you can check with your
system is 64 bit or 32 bit it says here
system type 64 bit operating 6 64 bit
operating system
ok so let's go ahead and close this
because we are not going to needed I'll
just minimize life file browser dare and
let's go ahead and downloaded so for
Windows 64 bit just go ahead and click
on it you will be redirected here it
says here download from Italy apparently
that's the closest to my current
location but you can go ahead and do dis
the link in new tab that's going to
prompt me to download it or I wanted to
begin your mirror am so sorry I just
clicked on it wrong choice it says or
pick a local mirror site below so done
with the leaders the cliffs and see how
easily erupt can deploy get it faster
here anyway so you have some things here
which are completely irrelevant for you
but down here it says choose a mirror
close to you take a look at these
countries here since says no you have a
lot of them
United Kingdom Germany Sweden whatever
and then you have North America here for
it
think of where you are in the world in a
physical sense and figure out which of
these locations is geographically
closest to you in order to increase the
speed of your download for me it says
okay this is this is your choice but you
can change it down below but i just i
just basically clicking on it no big
deal like this
and you will be prompted to download
Eclipse immediately go back to choose a
mirror and just gonna go ahead and
downloaded from the link that for
suggested to me just go ahead and click
on it that's all you need to do make
sure to select Save File and not open
file so save it may take a bit of time
for a deal I already have that would
have done that so the company canceled
this or something like that
not sure you might be prompted to
actually give some donations or
something of a kind
site but it doesn't feel it's not
mandatory or anything of a client you
can donate if you like if not its fine
you get all the features with you donate
or not completely irrelevant in terms of
functionality just go ahead and check if
I have it from my previous downloads
while it was running some tests he said
don't need to do I have it yes I do
excellent so I already have it
downloaded I don't need to do it again
so let's save some time just gonna go
ahead and close this the download file
which took from the net will be in your
downloads folder by default unless
you've actually changed it so just
here's how you would access it just go
ahead and click on downloads and then
find it here there you go
eclipse down below now I noticed that
the file is zipped so you need to open
up to you to unpack the files first
there are various tools to do this I'm
just go ahead and show you
virus running here so seven zip
that search engine that is the virus
that infects Firefox on Windows seven
messing around in open exposing the
machines as this is my test machine and
there is literally nothing of importance
here but I can't do without that they
don't have elsewhere anyway so go ahead
and click on Settings it this is also a
free software for you to unpack if you
don't already have one most likely have
something like wind which is a paid
version where you have seen as a poor
you have something else that's
completely irrelevant so you have the
exact file here the inner thigh or down
below you have the beta for windows I
really wouldn't recommend downloading
beaten just go ahead and say download on
. exam and that's it
download size is one megabyte she's
nothing just go ahead and run 26 file
software and their ago this is the
installation procedure going through its
going through thank you finish so you
don't need to follow this step if you
already have a software which you can
use to unzip a package if you don't have
to if you don't have a thought returns
at the package feel free to follow this
through or feel free to use any other
software to unzip that's completely up
to you
ok so let's go ahead and minimize this
and go ahead and open up 77 should pop
up
file manager takes me straight away to
down those which is very nice to have it
configured from before but if it doesn't
just change the path that whatever you
like or just save file open and then I
didn't find it doesn't really matter
just a pin the path where this file is
literally all you need to do
ok so but just double you don't even
need to type it in but just double
clicking on it you can actually browse
the file system and find whatever it is
that you're looking for anyway so let's
find a glimpse here and ok so let's just
expand this exon so we have eclipsed CPP
mars win32 x86 64 zip that is exactly
what I want to go ahead and click on
extract it says that its want to extract
into downloads again basically I'm gonna
go ahead and change that because I don't
want to do extracted downloads folder
head and I already have some
configuration files from before when I
was testing it out but I would like to
extracted to stop you can extract it
anywhere like create a shortcut on
desktop whatever you wish but for
testing purposes here I will go ahead
and its extracted so click on OK and ok
again
extraction process will be in drug
shouldn't take too long again this is
extracted anywhere you like to program
to program files or something of a calm
but I'm just gonna go ahead extracted to
desktop since it doesn't really matter
I'm just using this for educational
purposes anyway it's not like this is my
main machine tend to be a bit disorderly
they're probably something you can do
probably something that you can do
without so let's just let it run for a
little while not exactly the smallest of
packages
opinions of packaging this is not a
fascist of machines because the virtual
machine again so please take that into
consideration I have a signed a second
CPU core to it
expedite process you do not need to
deliver just finally single CPU core
that's done you can close the sentence
if you have eclipsed here and now we're
gonna get an error you have eclipsed
except just put it on the stock closed
this animal so going to benefit the
taskbar anyway so go ahead and double
click on it and you'll get an error that
says Java Runtime Environment or Java
Development Kit must be available no
problems let's go over to the net yet so
Java SE development kit 7 downloads
so where is it those clothes that are so
windows 64 so this is a Windows x64 and
we're just have a look at it
know this kid no not needed ok this is
the first the first version is the 32
bit the second version is 64 bit I'm not
mistaken I could be don't don't hate me
for it if I am just choose the I'm gonna
go ahead and choose the later one so the
last 12 Road go ahead and click on it so
you must accept the license agreement
for downloading I accept unknown license
agreement which no one in this world
treats and god knows what works what we
are
anyway you have chosen to open it
ok so save file its reporting it
requires four minutes for download that
differently consumes a little bit of
time but fortunately disease necessary
amount of time required for the download
to proceed
later on in Eclipse even though we will
need to even do we have everything
installed we have eclipsed the salt we
have Java SE development get to the
background we still need the compiler
something that will basically make
whatever is right whatever code rewrite
understandable to a machine to machine
can stand would rewrite and for Windows
you have a ton to do you have these
you have multiple compilers for it you
have one from Microsoft up to go ahead
and use an open source one which is
basically which was basically ported
over from Linux it's cold
doubly minimalist GNU for Windows ok so
you're here on their website so that
only from the official website www min
Zhu W dot org and we have download
installer would you like to do that we
would like to do that indeed far right
corner is the download going to start
with you are redirected to source for us
because we're going to pull it from
there is need to wait a couple of
seconds for it happen W get excellence
received the filed that's gonna start
downloading as well but that's really
fast just go ahead and click on it
of you license no problems gonna click
on install just leave everything as it
is
do not change you can change it but a
cause you a world of hurt later on like
this you simplify to a large extent go
ahead and click on Continue now because
I've already done some installations and
this can happen even if you didn't do
any installations just asking me whether
I would like to run it now
reinstall it or change directory quit
and just gonna go ahead and click on
reinstall if this doesn't happen to you
ok just text or whatever pops no big
deal
the installation process is underway so
this is the installation process
ways of savings already have it
installed installing gay so doing this
the browser and we are done so click on
Continue something happening over there
ok so we are now in mean min Zhu W
Installation Manager and virtually all
of these are green but they won't be
able to be for you so all you need to do
is right click on this and then go mark
for installation click on that it will
become green next one mark for
installation click all of them in that
fashion so once again on D it's not
going to be green for you so just go
ahead and right click on it
click on mark for installation and then
it's going to go ahead and install the
packages so all of them you need to
select all of them go ahead and click on
installation in the upper left corner it
once you have selected all of them
Indy basic setup you have all packages
here but you don't really care about
that at the moment would you care about
is basic setup click on installation say
Update Catalog
exxon so update is complete please close
the dialog to continue
that's it
so it might take a bit longer for you if
you get prompted with anything just say
okay next whatever doesn't really matter
that much anyway it's just gonna go
through and caused these things are not
installed in your system they're gonna
it's gonna take awhile you know to pool
the information necessary for all of
this and install it if you encounter any
problems with this step just a few
screenshots let me know what you did and
we got stuck I will be more than happy
to help you out pretty simple just like
on installation Update Catalog once
again it's gonna run through and that's
it might get prompted with another
window if it's the first time insulation
no big deal just click Apply and next
that's all you need to do no big deal
there and it will take a bit longer time
you might wanna go and make a cup of
coffee while it finishes but to save
time I already have the package is
installed and just repeating the process
within still pictures anyway just go
ahead and close this because we no
longer need that lets see how do we
stand
clips download with the with the Java
Runtime Environment ok so this is my
troubleshooting browser no problems
there still were to respond okay so judy
is here has been downloaded just go
ahead and click on it again should be
fine
feel their part should pop up any moment
there we go so yes pairing to install
ok should next next
that's all we need to do just click on
Next thats windows for you probably why
so many people use it was just keep on
clicking Next for pretty much everything
sometimes you can listing stuff like
that but most of the time just tends to
work out although I do find it
frustrating as it doesn't give me as
much control as I would like
anyway I am running a little bit short
on time here so I will pause at Royal
here