Welcome back everybody
I have really done nothing here, other than just wait for it to finish
and that's it
and then you get prompted with this window here, once it is done.
Yep, it's running in the background as well.
It's just waiting for me to set a path for it.
You can change it here.
Don't. There is no need.
Just go ahead and click on Next
3 Billion Devices Run Java
Yes, most of them smartphones/
Okay, so it's finishing...
You can feel free to read the text below if that entertains you.
Anyway, successfully installed Java SE development kit.
Click on Next Step to access tutorial, api documentation, etc.
We are not going to do that at the moment.
So go ahead and click on Close
Now we have Java installed and we have a
compiler installed guess what your
journey has not ended in terms of
setting up your environment so we still
need to we still need to do a couple of
things here and one of them being is
that we need to set up our environment
variables and what I mean by that is the
following so in de Vigo to see see it
says here
GEW but nobody else on the system
nobody else but for example eclipses are
word integrated development environment
doesn't really know where W is it has no
idea of what so ever that is located
here also the PATH variable is w is not
included in the PATH variable and gonna
go ahead and show you what that is here
so just go ahead and click in the bottom
left
Warner go ahead and select system and
then we're going to go ahead and click
on advanced system settings by the way
maybe this is not the best way to
actually show it but away some of the
people might be using Windows seven or
later versions so this would be an
easier way to do it if you just go ahead
and open up your file explorer like this
you are here at this beginnings page so
go ahead and right click on this PC or
Mac computer which averages go ahead and
click on Properties click on Advanced
Settings button below it says
environment variables go into system
variables sell one random
press D and you will be directed to path
now let's go ahead and edited the
letters will be small here and that can
be annoying I know I will zoom in for
you so let's just show you what is
located here
notepad ok so this is something that we
will need to do in a moment I would
really like to open up another note pad
pasted increase a 15 year ago so want to
go to 22 well what's going on further
let's go let's be in knots let's go with
28 hopefully this is large enough for
everybody to see if extended to the end
of my screen is able to fit it basically
this first line is what you are what you
will be any the semicolon as well
your ass will look like this what you
need to do is control V in order to
control the answer to this so yours will
be something like this basically all of
these things it doesn't matter how it
looks like I don't really care all you
need to do is at the beginning just
insert this lines capital C
colon back / min Zhu W backslash in
semicolon do not touch anything else
there is no need for you to do so and
needed you don't see that that is what
you need to do where these very small
letters are written so at the beginning
you need to insert this line as you can
see I haven't heard it I have copied
this to note that said you can all see
it here it's probably too small for you
to see but doesn't matter I have showed
you the whole text in Notepad have shown
you what you need to do once you have
done that
click on OK
ok gettin and you will have the option
to apply it here since you actually done
some changes ahead and click on it and
then click on OK again however our
journey does not end here now that we
have done all of this we are finally
finally ready to open up clips let's go
ahead and click on OK here now it is a
starting it goes it
6056 5060 CPU usage is used 70% believe
that I was signed Li Xin just speed
things along
rate so there it is it's running its see
running under Java says it's not
responding with says oh well I'm not
responding but it actually is so just
let it run is it maxes out CPU until it
starts and actually it should drop it is
resource intensive and still it is 5030
and I was dropping because we're not
doing anything in it so I have the small
program here which is a default one but
let's go ahead and delete this project I
will go ahead and this project you won't
have it so delete
and if you get greeted we do welcome
screen he can just close it is see here
it's as Project Explorer and then you
have this close button
well if you click Close you're going to
close it if you get greeted with a
welcome screen where it wants to show
you things around so on and so forth
go ahead and click on this text and
closed till it don't be nice now let's
go ahead and click on File in the upper
left corner select new C++ project cuz
we want to create a C++ project by the
way before we continue just let me tell
you that there are numerous other idea
environments eclipse is very popular you
also have NetBeans which is extremely
popular as well and you have code blocks
a little bit less popular as it somewhat
limited in features and you also have
the Visual Studio Microsoft Visual
Studio 2008 I do believe it's free so
how do you like or you can actually well
the 2012 you have to buy its greats has
a lot of features but believe me there's
no need for you to do that eighty
percent of those features you will not
eclipse is just fine
can pretty much do whatever you want
with it so let's go ahead and named our
project how shall we name our project
well let's name it he maybe not yet hold
it down to just create one particular
project which I going to use and then we
will alter it in play around with it and
so on and so forth
let's go ahead and tape in key
we're not gonna start coding the
keylogger just yet I just name the
project you longer or I could have a
good have named it mary jane whatever I
want to do it could have been aimed at
by some of the things I see a light
table coffee cup of coffee or the really
old coffee that behind the screen may
need to remove one of these days anyway
let's go ahead you can select an empty
project if you like but for the time
being I just like to say hello world C++
project so let's go ahead and and here
you will be able to select a compiler we
have installed min Zhu W GCC can go
ahead and click on Next if you wish
there's no but you can also click on
Finish and be done with it I'm still ago
heading through this one so I can show
it to you
case to the author of the copyright
notice is a world treating you type in
here whatever you want
pretty sure that you'll know what these
options mean they're pretty self
explanatory click on Next and now you
have Debug and Release so what sort of
configuration would you like to have
when you compile it is it for release
release means that you are ready to
deploy it and it's pretty much the final
version of the product while the final
version but it's it's the version that
you're going to use any real system
outside of urine test environment and
debug is basically just what we will be
using now mainly because we were still
in the process of creation using the
debug basically the the word tells you
what it is it's the bugging so it's
finding these these problems the code
you are doing all of that the idea is
hoping you well once all of that is done
go to the release for him and you pilot
so let's go ahead in like
finish all done fine and dandy now we
need to go ahead and set some right here
so going to file and then going to
properties C++ bill go down where it's
setting said he believed was this one
resource that's why I like having the
stupid file because I don't forget these
things
path and file properties ok so where is
it
symbols could it be that is this year
I'm pretty sure I'm using the wrong run
preprocessor include paths have to be
here you absolutely have to be here and
be a serious man by pattern
properties let's see here we go
so small correction here my bad I went
on to file you need to go on to your
project name here at ski lockers right
click on it
a sincerely apologize for this just what
to do and go down into properties all of
this will be closed so we will have seen
/ C++ will go ahead and expand that go
into environment here so there we go so
click on it and once again we will have
the same thing here let's go ahead and
call PETA into pat so this is the file
that we have here its large it's tedious
and cumbersome go ahead and read through
it if you wish but this is the portion
that we need and please feel free to
copy it into this file for me it's here
in the center I do believe it's been
shaken up but you can feel free to get
pretty much the same position as I have
just after after just a tad here all you
need to do is they've been capital C
colon backslash GEW backslash been
remember to have a colon at the end if
you're putting it at the beginning if
you're putting it in the end of the
semicolon at D at the beginning so that
or if you're putting it indeed
if you're sorry for putting it in the
beginning so like this I don't think
it's gonna make a difference sometimes
it tends to cause some problems begin at
the beginning but no big deal they're
just put it in like this and you will
save yourself a lot of problems for me
it's here doesn't matter if it doesn't
work out for you in the beginning try
putting it in the same position as I
have but I was talking about these
semicolons if you put it here in the
beginning you need is some like gold at
the end the separated from the rest but
if you put it in the end like this you
need a semi cool in the beginning and
you do not need a semicolon and just
keep that in mind do not save it so
that's all we need to do with this with
the spat variable and then click on k
see because it's very small size in
notepad but you just go ahead and see
what you can do with error I don't know
go really really really close to the
screen and try to do it on your own
computers I do not know why they made it
so small it can be annoying as hell but
what can you do about it
go ahead and click on once you are done
with that ok so we need to do one more
thing what was it
binary Fraser ok so it is this one
should be
no no no no no man this is embarrassing
beyond belief is preferred start as you
can see it happens to the best of us I
swear I will not edit the subtle just
leave it i dont no way I hope that it
will make somebody laugh and if you're
super quick to follow through the
tutorials and click on things ourselves
if you make the same mistake I will die
laughing on the other side no big deal
you won't lose anything
the settings will be saved as you can
see just brings you back to the same
thing and all loss has occurred but as
you can see stupid things happen to
everybody
happen to everybody so don't worry about
it no big deal there let's see this one
should be in file properties property
file properties thank you Bill settings
there we go so go into C++ build and
then go into settings and then go into
binary raises make sure that the P E
windows Fraser is so like this just
click on OK the trip I do not believe
that there is anything else that we need
to do there is a hammer for building in
the upper left close to the upper left
corner you need to build everything
before you can actually run it so go
ahead and click on the hammer away then
click on the hammer
you can of course but the corruption is
control the building everything so
control the is built and it says here
bill out with what it has done
internal builder is used to build and
that it is using the ok so no problems
there you don't actually you don't
really care about this part this is
something you sort of commands are
things that you would use in the next to
make sure that I D problem or that you
don't have any problems with the idea
you can also compel these things but
that's irrelevant for the time being
let's go ahead and click on run so there
was this really a green play button that
I'm selecting now if I click on it if
this happens to you just rebuild that
what you go so you just click on the
green one if you get an error message
like I did just rebuild it for the
control of you couple of times that
should be fine this is our first program
it says hello world that's for the
program is supposed to do I will start
explaining this and how it all works out
in the fall tutorial until then I'm all
farewell