Hello, everybody, and welcome to
this last tutorial of the course.
Today, I will show you how you can upload
a reverse shell onto a web server.
However, there are multiple problems here.
First of all, the filtering of extensions.
So, for example, I have on my desktop,
have a nice day .php,
and then I have something here,
which I have clearly striped.
So backslash.
Excellent, so this is a reverse shell of
which I have added the extension GPG,
primarily because,
web servers they have Filters.
And let's just open up our vulnerable app.
There's this neat upload section.
Now, somebody might say well we're not
gonna get that from a real web server, or
website, my answer to this, yes you will.
Why?
Well, pretty much all social websites and
any sort of a website,
that has client to client interaction.
And any sort of website which has
tech support of that kind and
which has contact forums,
there's a 99% chance there will be
an upload function somewhere on the site.
Just have a look around.
It's there almost all the sites have
an upload function of some sort or kind.
Okay, just take a try to
imagine a dating website.
How would a dating website function,
without an upload function
to upload photos of people?
Practically impossible.
Also, social media websites and so on.
There are several things which you
need to take into consideration.
One of them is you need to figure out
which version of PHP are they running.
To do that, you will have an nmap scan.
And you have script equals
http-php-version, and this is gonna give
you a version of HTTP, and it's gonna try
to determine which operating system is
running there as well,
if I'm not mistaken.
But more importantly, it will give you
a PHP version of the web server, and
then based upon the version of the PHP,
you will be able to exercise
certain vulnerabilities.
So, my version, you can find
the script on the Nmap website.
Just type into Google, or
whatever search engine you are using.
Nmap PHP version scan and
it will bring you there.
I hope that you know
how to do that by now.
If you want to check which
PHP version you are using,
type in php5-V, and there you go.
So let's see, php 5.4.
So 5439.
You think that 53,
something like that was
vulnerable to no byte inclusion.
This is what I was trying
to do here previously.
You have, for example, php/00.jpg.
This thing would be dropped, and
even though it would be recognized.
Truncated the last part anyway,
but the web server would, the PHP,
would actually read in the JPEG and
it would say, this is fine.
And then you would have a PHP script,
somewhere on the server, which amazing.
Okay, so first thing's first.
We need to actually our reverse shell.
Go ahead and type in 10 test
monkey php refer let's see.
Php-reverse-shell, pentestmonkey.
And there we go.
So you have php-reverse-shell-1.0 tar.gz.
Go ahead and click on it.
Okay, save file.
Go ahead and open it up.
Click on it, extract.
I'll type in quit.
Go to your downloads folder.
It should be here around somewhere.
Excellent.
So, in the downloads folder,
I have PHP reverse shell 1.0, what.
1.0 actually.
Nothing else.
Anyway, you have some files
here that you can read.
Those are license things and
there's a change log as well.
But, this is what you're interested in.
PHP reverse shell.
You can copy it to a folder
that is appropriate to you.
That is completely up to you.
I have copied mine onto desktop.
You can see it here.
I just renamed it into have a nice day.
You can rename it whatever you want,
as long as it's not PHP.
And then you don't need to
put this note right here.
So, let me just rename.
Excellent, so it's .php and
I have .jpeg, but let's delete .jpeg for
the time being, and let's leave it at
.php, and let's see what happens here.
Where is it?
I have so many things open down here.
Keep in mind that when you're
attempting a pen test and
when you're attempting to do this,
what I'm doing now,
you won't be able to do this on
the latest version of PHP so, no way.
Very difficult,
you're better off with an SQL injection,
than you are with what I am attempting
to do now, this is just so.
You can conduct a scan of a few servers,
or a mass scan because, well, not
saying that you should scan the servers
that you don't have permission to scan.
But people have been doing
mass scan of the servers,
and they've been figuring out which
PHP versions they are running.
And if they see they've
made these scripts.
It's a pretty simple script.
It basically says if the version
is lower than this number,
give me the IP address, and
attempt to do the following.
Believe it or not, there are a lot of
servers out there which are not updated.
Obviously, not Facebook, or obviously, not
Google or Twitter or something like that.
But still a large amount of sites
would be vulnerable to something
of that kind, and I would strongly suggest
that you take a look at null bite.
So just, null bite.
That is the thing that you saw in
my file name a moment ago, like,
back dot PHP/00.jpg.
That's gonna work on just a little
bit older versions of PHP so
if somebody didn't do
the latest updates or
something of that kind, they're
gonna be in a ton load of problems.
Anyway, we're gonna go to browse,
have a nice day dot PHP,
open, we're gonna say upload.
You're image was not uploaded and for some
strange reason it's popping it up here.
I have no idea why?
It doesn't matter.
It says your image was not uploaded so
there was a problem.
Let's take a look at the source code.
Obviously on a real site you might,
well maybe not obviously, but
on a legit site you might not be able
to see this, the checking mechanism.
Anyway, it doesn't matter,
you have a way of assuming this.
So it says,
upload the type needs to be image and
jpeg and
upload size needs to be lesser than this.
So, what shall we do when
we can't actually see this?
Well, go the the Upload function and
try uploading different file formats.
Don't just try the standard ones,
try whatever you can.
Try the unorthodox ones,
try the weaker ones, etc.
Whatever you can, try to upload it,
see what kind of error messages you get.
And, if you are unable to
upload one type of file, but
you are able to upload
another type of file,
you will see what the filters are like,
and what they are doing.
And if you try to upload files of
certain size, you don't need to try
to upload 100 of them, you can just try to
upload those that are equal to the size
of your reverse shell, or that are greater
than the size of your reverse shell.
In such a case you will
be able to determine,
whether you will be able to
upload your reverse shell or not.
In case that your reverse shell is
significantly bigger than the size
allowed, look for
another shell that's smaller.
These things are pretty small anyway.
So what shall we do?
We shall go to Edit > Preferences
> Advanced > Network > Settings.
Manual proxy configuration,
type in 127001 and for Port 8080.
Press OK.
Close.
We're gonna start a burpsuite.
Takes a while to load,
but well worth the wait.
Anyway, we're going to intercept
the request in BurpSuite, and
then we're going to alter it a bit,
you might have noticed that I'm using
the media setting on the downloadable app,
primarily because you are not going to
be able to do this, on high setting.
There is no way, if you manage to do it,
feel free to post it on the net,
it will be a zero day vulnerability,
and you will get the credit for it.
Anyway so it's target, click on Proxy.
Options, make sure that this
one is ticked 127001:8080.
Go back to intercept.
Go back to the browser.
Not this one.
Excellent.
Now, what we shall do is also rename
the file as I have renamed it before.
Dot, what shall we name it, jpg.
And even though you see some sort of
a picture here you're not gonna be
able to open it on site, I'll show you.
So where is it?
Okay, so browse. Open.
Click on Upload and now go into berg suit.
Here you're going to be able
to reformulate the request,
and to tell it pretty
much whatever you want.
So it says content disposition
form data name uploaded.
File name, haveaniceday.php.jpg.
Remove the jpg from this and
then say forward.
Tell me it was uploaded.
Yes it was.
Excellent.
We're gonna go ahead and copy this part,
so we see the place where it
was actually uploaded.
Ups we don't actually in the JPG.
Excellent and
prior to this what I've done.
I mean this is generally not
necessary now primarily,
because we are connecting back to
ourselves, but take a look at this.
Now, this is what I've done prior, if
you're doing this on two virtual machines,
or something like that,
you're gonna need to change it.
I'm doing it on one, so
it doesn't really matter that much.
You enter the file, you edit it with Nano,
and there is this part,
where it says change this, quite literally
and it says here change this as well.
So here you need to change the IP address
to the IP address that is appropriate.
I have changed it previously, but
it was also global host site IP address.
As I said it doesn't matter to me now,
because I'm connecting to myself.
But if you're doing this
on two virtual machines and
you most likely will- and in reality you
will be doing this over the internet.
You will need to change this
to an appropriate IP address.
Also you can change the port if you wish,
I wouldn't recommend using these
default ports for anything.
So it's one, two, three, four.
Change it to whatever you want,
you can put eight-eight-eight or whatever.
Anyway control x since that is
already changed next up we need
to use a bit of knowledge that we
harvested in the previous tutorial so
net cat n cat give me verbosity
level increase verbosity level
give me demoed go into listening mode Give
me the port on which you're gonna listen.
It's gonna be 1234,
press enter and
now it is listening on port 1234.
Now let's give it k for, there's no need,
let's just leave it as it is.
You see I change my mind quite often.
Anyway, now that we have this math,
you can type it in here.
See it's spinning, and
where is the terminal
nope that [INAUDIBLE] Okay so
it should be listening and
the burp suite of course is not
forwarding that was the problem so
forward exon there we go now we have
a connection to the web server and
can't access tty job control turned off So
now problems.
Give me LSTC.
I have access.
So lets go to root of stab does not work.
Root, and
it stands to reason that doesn't work.
Desktop.
Press enter.
LS.
There we go.
We have successfully made it full circle.
And now we are in.
Have a nice day.
php.jpg.
From this point on, you can do
whatever you want to the machine.
This was an example for virtual on Linux.
Linux systems and
operating systems are not invulnerable,
in spite of what the internet
has been saying.
They are also full of vulnerabilities.
But they get patched really fast though.
Primarily because it's an open source,
community works, non-stop on it.
And vulnerabilities are discovered really
fast and patched really fast as well.
So it's a very secure
system in that sense.
Microsoft is a bit slower, if I'm not
mistaken, in patching these things.
Probably because it costs money and
for Linux it's practically free.
Thanks to thousands of
volunteers worldwide who do it.
But anyway.
Keep in mind that Linux is not beyond,
is not unbreakable, impregnable.
It's not invulnerable.
It's an operating system like any other.
It has flaws, you cannot prove that
it's impossible to break into it,
you can only prove that it is
possible to break into it.
In any case I would like to
say goodbye to everybody,
in the sense of tutorials, but I will.
I'm always around in
the discussion section.
So feel free to ask as many
questions as you would like to.
And I do encourage you to
explore new things and
you can feel free to ask
me about them if you have.
If you're doing some pen testing that is
perhaps not related or not included in
this tutorial even though I've included
pretty much whatever I I could think of.
Feel free to post such questions, as well.
They do not necessarily need to be
related directly to what I am doing here,
although I do not vouch for those answers.
But I will give my best
to help you out there.
If you ask about something
within this tutorial,
I'll be able to help you there 100%.
anyway, until the next course or something
of that kind I bid you all farewell.
And I thank you for watching