Welcome back everybody.
So this process has finished and you're supposed to get a output like this.
Cohen took three point on gigabytes.
Let's take this one more time.
And we see that it has created this has created two partitions.
No big deal there.
That's supposed to go like that.
So let's go ahead and clear the screen and start you parse it one more time.
Wait for it to start.
Select this TB X on.
So there is the boot partition.
There is the color you live FAT 32 and then we have 55 gigabytes of allocated space.
So we will format this to a different type of a partition but let's first take a look at what guide
what the guide says.
I believe they have instructed us to formatted as ex-state 3 instead of 64.
I suppose it's due to some compatibility issues or something of a kind.
Even this is FAT 16 instead of FAT 32 but ok.
No big deal there.
Let's go back to their site and see what else do we have to do.
So as far as the as far as the storage is concerned as far as the live US is concerned that would literally
be it as far as this guy says and I haven't detested this out at this point of time.
There is nothing else that you need to do.
You can just literally plug your you is me into your machine and set your physical machine to boot for
me you will be in bio in BIOS on Dell machines because I have a Dell machine.
You press F 2 or F F 12 at boot time and you can select the boot options on some other machines something
like Acer or HP.
You use different keys but no worries.
Just reboot the machine and you will see the key.
Like somewhere in the bottom right corner or the bottom left corner somewhere at butan you will see
press to enter setup or something anyway.
So as I said there is nothing else that you need to do.
This is it.
You now have a live Juez B.
However if you would like to have some persistent storage.
Well that's another thing entirely.
And let's go about things.
So let's go ahead and find the guide for persistent storage.
I just want you to be able to use that as a reference.
So I'm just going to type it in here.
Culley next to us the file systems
is this.
Yup this is the one.
So look it says call it Linux Live has two options the default boot menu which enable persistence.
So first of all you have the life persistence and the live use be it cryptic persistence.
I would I would personally recommend that you just use the live use be persistence.
You can go with the encrypted one as well but that is completely your choice.
So you know what let's go ahead and see how this works with the Locsin encryption.
However you know if you forget your key if you don't use your USP for a while or something like that
and you forget your key you will never again.
And I mean never again if you've selected the complicated enough in a long enough encryption key you
will never again be able to access that information will be lost to you gone completely.
So please keep that in mind because when creating encrypted things if you're going to use it fine.
No problems if you're not going to use it and you're going to leave it standing somewhere lying around
somewhere and forget the key and then lose all your data.
Think about it.
Is it really worth it.
Do you have anything on that stick that's that important that you absolutely need to encrypt the data
much.
Think about it just see if it's worth it at all.
So let's go and see what the guy below says both guides are fairly similar and they function on very
similar costs.
They function in a very similar concept.
They just use a bit of a different partitioning.
So alternatively you can create Luxon encrypt persistent storage area.
This is an extra layer of security.
And the following example.
OK so what does it say will create a new partition to store a persistent data and starting right above
the second call the life dition and then adding 70 gigabytes.
So you don't really need this.
So we're just going to go ahead and skip that set up blocks encryption and you partition put the next
default system on it and create persistence dot com file.
Ok so this persistence can file.
We will definitely need this and we will need a Luchs setup.
So they have this command that you can I'm pretty sure you can copy this or anything of a kind.
So it's not going to work the way you want it to work.
So that's why we're going to have to do this ourselves down below.
So we have crypto set up and system to set up looks open.
OK so devastated B-3 my USPSA That's the third partition.
So we need to make a partition.
Open it up with locks and well formatted with locks then open it with locks that formatted with exit
three false system.
Give it a label and then we need to create this persistence file here and then we need to go ahead and
close it once it's closed just reboot the machine and the next time it boots just select the live use
be with persistence alive is be with persistent encrypted Ligers be with persistence and you will be
prompted for a key.
And now I can't really show this as I'm recording so I'll see if I can use my cell phone camera to record
the screen as I boot because keep in mind when you put a live version of Cali you're going to encounter
some problems for the very first problem that you will encounter is if you're working on multiple screens
like I.
Yeah.
Cali live Cali is just not going to see them.
So you can kiss that goodbye.
This is primarily for you using it on your laptop or your desktop machine somewhere.
It will not work with multiple monitor setups.
Also you might encounter some problems with Wi-Fi.
That just means that you don't have the proper drivers installed.
That is it for Wi-Fi use be adapters you can go ahead and check out lecture's 35 and 36.
I do believe that I have explained it in great detail.
Which one you can use that is practically guaranteed to work although there are other ones that are
guaranteed to work as well.
I just picked that one because it was cheap and it was supplied in great abundance on eBay.
So let's let's begin shall we.
So that's part of it.
And we're not going to need you parted now.
I just want these things here.
So show what shall we do first step in this space of this space.
Well OK so it says the b f this space of STV open it up press.
And because we wanted to create a new one it will be a primary partition.
You can have four primary partitions partition numbers so its default is three.
Because look we already have one and then we have two.
And since you can only have four it's one to four.
And we're going to go ahead and create a third one.
So three first sector.
OK the first sector is the last sector of SATB.
So you can see that this one and this one are pretty much the same so it just this one ends.
But for this was in answer to 103.
So just the next one that's fine just press enter and now you can define the size so it's as a last
sector plus sectors or plus size.
So look you can basically if you don't want to take your entire week type in plus and then see then
gee that would b plus then gigabytes.
Sorry let me just explain this
what is the problem.
Sorry that seems to have gotten stuck.
So new primary three term
exons So now I can say it like plus 10 G and B plus them gigabytes and that would be the next partition
or I could actually specify the set of sectors I would like but I would just like it to basically take
the rest of my the rest of available space.
So this is the last possible secretary that is going to take and this will be the occupied sectors there
should be roughly around.
I don't know let's see maybe 40 gig 40 50 gig or something like that doesn't really matter it's just
going to take the rest of the space that's available just press enter and use the default one says using
default value.
Now press W2 right.
OK so warning.
Rereading the two filters 16 device or resource busy the kernel still use the old table.
OK so let's go ahead and type in the space age
CB2 is mounted amount of too.
I don't really want it.
OK so let's go ahead and attempt this again the full.
Hopefully it has loaded its part.
Will you succeed.
Unable to.
OK.
So we have successfully done that found a mistaken if this space dush else.
Yup we have.
So we indeed have managed to formatted format formatted we have managed to partition it and we have
gotten that extra partition.
So the next steps that we're going to need to do.
I'm just going to go ahead and use this use a little bit of this guide here because I honestly haven't
used locks.
I haven't formatted anything with locks in a really long time primarily because I didn't really need
to form a hidden thing with Luxx you usually do it once when you install your system and you don't do
it like ever again because there is no need.
You're only going to encrypt your drives once and that's it.
You're never going to mess with them again.
And that's exactly what I'm saying.
So if you don't use them on a daily basis or something like that if you have a complex key out you're
most likely going to have to say goodbye to your data at a certain point of time.
OK so now I can just pretty much copy paste this command because my drive my partition is called S-D
beat.
If yours is called differently please change accordingly.
Base it's crypto set up for Bowse verify password locks formats and we're just formatting this with
locks and a partition is Esty the device is a sleepy and the partition is three.
Please verify that this is the device and that this is the partition because yours might be different.
Could be the D-3 or Esti C-3 or something of a kind.
I don't know.
Just check.
Most likely will be the same but check it anyway.
Let's go ahead and press enter.
Warning it will overwrite the data.
Yes command failed in voevoda argument.
Got them on the ass.
Enter a passphrase so I'm going to go ahead and type in test.
Be very very careful what you type in here.
Once locked once encrypted if the password is complex enough you will never again be able to decrypt
it without a proper passphrase.
So forget about if you saw the thing in the movies like when they break the encryption on the drive
or something like it.
It just doesn't happen if the passphrase is complex enough.
It doesn't matter how fast your computer is it doesn't.
You can use the Google data center and utilize all the processors and all the old the graphics cards
and GPU use and use and whatever else you can think of and you can generate billions upon billions upon
billions upon billions of passwords and keys a second would take you about 20 years to decrypt.
He could pass a good key.
So yeah imagine how long it would take like a regular PC to do it.
Like forget about that that's one of that's one of the reasons I'm mistaken like in some countries where
the authorities can hold the encrypted drives indefinitely because it takes a ridiculous amount of time
to decrypt them and it's even questionable whether ever they will be decrypted because of the amount
of resources that have to be devoted to such a task.
Again I repeat myself I'm really sorry if I'm boring or something like that but it's very important
today to remember the passphrase because you won't be able to come to me in the discussion section and
say hey you know my passphrase doesn't work.
So I'm not going to be able to do anything about it.
It doesn't matter if my remote into your system or something like that completely irrelevant.
There will be nothing and I mean literally nothing that I will be able to do about it.
Please remember it a passphrase if you are opting for this setup or just type in something extremely
simple that you will be able to remember anyway enough about it enough about my Enough of my paranoid
chatter here.
Let's go ahead and do this.
So why is it called My b.
Have you made it.
OK.
So you can let it be my USPS fine.
So enter passphrase.
What is the passphrase that you just typed in.
There we go.
We have managed to open it.
If you fail if you fail this this one that you typed in here and this one for disks they are exactly
the same.
So no worries there.
And now we can go ahead and create this we can format it.
So just go ahead and formatted with extra 3 with label persistence.
And this is the device that we will be formatting.
This should take a while.
I mean it shouldn't take too long but it's going to take a while.
Definitely.
Sorry that's come on come on come on come C'mon.
It really hit it right in the middle of a story.
Get a waiting thing like this.
And you have done some test runs without the encryption so without the encryption everything seemed
to have worked out just fine without any problems.
And the principle is exactly the same.
All you need to do is create another partition.
The only difference between this one and the one without encryption is basically the locks set up so
that the data would be encrypted.
That's it.
But it's not a bad idea.
I mean it's a good concept to protect your information and all of that.
But in any case I am running out of time and I don't think this is going to finish in any reasonable
amount of time.
At some point of time I swear I'm going to get to another computer and I'm going to have the Senate
running as a virtualise which is going to work crazy fast because it gives like 95 percent of native
performance anyway.
I'm going to bid you farewell here and then we're going to continue in the follow up to Tauriel.
And before I leave.
I sincerely hope that the God that I have chosen is simple enough and the set up is simple enough.
If you would like me to create instructions for other other distributions as I have said feel free to
just let me know in the discussion section by.