fdisk
fdisk-l
sdb     gparted
GB55  Kali live    boot
ext 4    ext 3
fat 32   fat 16
live USB
USB
USB   boot
F12  F2     -DELL   - DELL
boot       boot
HP  acer
boot
live USB
Kali Linux USB persistence
Kali Linux live
live persistence, live USB encrypted persistence
live USB persistence
LUKS
USB
GB   7 Kali live
ext 3          "
"  persistence.conf
persistenc.conf
LUKS
cryptsetup
cryptsetup luksOpen /dev/sdb3 my_usb
LUKS
ext 3          LUKS
persistence.conf
boot
encrypted live USB with persistence
live Kali   boot
live Kali
WiFi
WiFi USB adapters
35 36
gparted
fdisk -l
n    fdisk /dev/sdb
primary partition   P
primary partitions   4
3    1  2
4   3
sdb2
103 104
Enter
last sector, +sector or +size
+10G
Enter   3  p  n
40  50
Enter
W
"    .....    ....."
df -h
mounted   sdb2
umount /dev/ sdb2
partprobe
fdisk -l
..
LUKS
sdb3
sdb3   LUKS
Enter
y
"   "
YES
test
-   -
-     -
:
my_usb
mkfs.ext3 -L persistence /dev/mapper/my_usb
%95