Okay, so – that took a lot of time to finish.
Not sure how long it took on your system,
but on mine it took a lot of time. I watched
like 10 YouTube videos or something like that.
I'm not sure how long they were, yet you get
the idea. Anyway, from here onward we can
just copy most of these commands. That's exactly
what I shall do. You can make own mount point
or you can just go ahead and copy this one.
I mean, no big deal-- whatever. Then we can
go ahead and mount this one. Since we used
the same names, we can just copy and paste.
Let's just verify. Yes, there we go. The mount
has went up perfectly. Then, we need to go
ahead and do this. We will echo this line
into this file located here. What is this
that I have selected now? That is the mount
point of our storage. So, my USB we have just
formatted with LUKS. We can feel free to unmount
it. First, press enter. Let's go ahead and
unmount it. Then, it says close the encrypted
channel to our persistent partition. We can
basically just go in to and close it with
crypt. Make sure to know the password. There
we go! This shouldn't be accessible anymore.
Then, that is literally it. There is nothing
else that you need to do here. I'll just go
ahead and explain a little bit with this portion
where you don't have encryption. I mean, it's
fairly similar, pretty much the same, actually.
Okay, I'll just go and see. This part, you
don't actually need to copy and paste. Just
go ahead and use the FDISK, as I have used
it, and create a another partition. So, that
that part is the same. Just use FDISK as we
have used it before.
Fdisk, space-- like this "fdisk /dev/DEVICENAME"
-- the device name should be USB or SDB or
whatever it is. You can figure out what it
is with "-L option" and see it here. So you
will need to format it. If it is SDB3, you
can go ahead and copy paste this. Then go
ahead and copy paste this as well. So, no
big deal there at all. Then, I just keep copy
pasting until the end. The only thing that
you will need to change it is SDB3-- maybe.
As I said, check it out with your fdisk and
figure out what it is. Just go ahead and create
a partition with fdisk, as I have shown as
I have showed you in the previous tutorial.
This segment here took a lot of time. I mean,
a lot! So don't be discouraged. If the thinking
that the system is blocked or there is a bug
or something. Know it just takes a lot of
time in a virtual machine. That's the fact
of the matter, and it has something to do
with the fact that I have a pretty large USB
stick. Anyway, keep all that in mind. Now,
everything is done here. I shall now reboot
it to my Kali machine. I will use my phone
just to give you some images. There is nothing
that you need to do pretty much. We've created
a live USB with encrypted persistence. Just
select live USB and encrypted persistence
when it boots. I'm going to do some shooting
with my phone. The image is not to be great
because my new phone is still not here and
this camera is terrible. It doesn't really
matter that much because there is nothing
that you need to do. Everything is set up.
Everything is ready. Everything is working.
All you need to do is boot from the new USB.
I'm just going to record it to prove that
it functions. If it doesn't function for you,
you might be doing something wrong. Let me
know in the discussion section. We'll discuss
it there and see how it works. Let me just
remind everybody
before we start that, you shouldn't expect
multiple monitors to work. That's just not
going to happen easily at all. You will need
to mess around with the drivers and personally
that's not a good idea, especially not for
a bootable USB. Second, if wireless doesn't
work, you need to fix that. You can do it
with drivers. Think about it for second. If
you have a wireless card within your machine
and doesn't support a lot of things, like
aircrack or something, or that is supported
in Kali. Why bother with the drivers at all,
if it's not going to connect. You'll still
be able to connect to the wireless access
point, but I mean you won't be able to do
half of the stuff with wireless, so why bother.
I suggest getting another wireless USB adapter
which you can just plug-n-play and it will
work. Anyway, I am going to close my virtual
machine and then I'm gonna go ahead and boot
from my USB drive and record this for my phone.
Please don't hang me if the images of the
qualities not super great or something like
that. From this point on, There is no more
configuration. There is nothing else to do
need to do. The only reason that I'm shooting
at this next segment is so I can show you
the the boot does indeed work. You can actually
boot from a live USB without any problems.
That it is functional, and the procedure is
working. So, let's get into that.