Hello everybody and welcome to this tutorial.
Today I am going to go ahead and just show
you that you can actually boot from this USB
stick. There is this is not a mandatory tutorial,
or anything like that. This is just to prove
that this is functional, and this method does
indeed work and that you can boot from the
USB state that we have created off Kali Linux
with encrypted persistent storage. I am going
to go ahead and plug it in. Then, I'm going
to go ahead and power on my laptop. I am using
a Dell laptop. For me, I need to press either
F2 or F12. I'm going to go ahead and press
F12 for start up options, since F2 is for
BIOS and F12 is for boot options on a Dell
machine. If you're using Acer or HP or something
of a kind, it might be different. It will
always be shown on the screen which keys can
you press for which options at boot. You see,
I've encountered this problem that I want
to share with you as well. I get a screen
like this when I select boot options, and
I cannot select the options. Do not immediately
assume you've done something wrong, that your
USB is not functional or something like that.
Instead, what you can do is just power off
the machine. No big deal. Power it back on
and enter BIOS. So for me, it's F2. There
is nothing you need to do in BIOS for it right
at the moment. Of course, if you wish, you
can select the default boot option to be the
USB. There it is on at the moment. I will
go over to boot. And there's the legacy boot
and then press enter. I don't see USB here.
Okay that's fine. Just press escape several
times until it says exit disregarding changes.
click, Yes. Control/alt/del to restart the
machine again. Then you can press the boot
options. There we go, so I have boot options
now. See it says USB storage device. I'm going
to go ahead and select it. Now, I have boot
options for Kali linux. I have boot from a
USB. I'm gonna go ahead and select live USB
encrypted persistence because that is the
one that we have chosen to create. Hopefully
that will be suitable for you as well. Go
ahead and press enter. So it's rolling and
rolling. I have other encrypted
partitions on this laptop, so it will ask me
if I want to decrypt them as well. I will
say no.  You will not encounter this unless
you have other encrypted partitions. It's
asking me to unlock my drive. I do not
wish to unlock it so, I press 'N' for no. Just
enter some random key, then press enter. Do this
again for SDA3. I do not wish to decrypt this
just press 'n' or yes. 'N' is for no and 'Y'
is for yes. If you want to retry the decryption
process. I would like to decrypt SDB3 because
that is my USB. You need to be familiar with
the partitioning scheme on the machine to
know which which ones do you wish decrypt.
Take a look at the output of FDISK space – L "fdisk -l"
as shown in the previous tutorials to figure
out how your USB partition is. Is it DEV SDA,
or is it DEV SDB? It can be DEV SDC or something
depending on what it is. It's telling me now,
please unlock disc DEV SDB3. I'm going to
type in my decryption key and press enter.
Don't worry if you can't see anything while
you're typing. It's perfectly fine. That is
the way it is supposed to be so that somebody
from behind
won't actually see the length of your key.
It's a security precaution, which I really
like in Linux. This is not the case in Windows
unfortunately, where the length of pretty
much anything you type and any passwords is
revealed. So I have my system. Now, my wireless
is working it says, "wireless networks available."
I'm not going to connect to any of them because
there is no point. The only thing that I'm
going to do now is create a file on my desktop
and then reboot the machine, so that you can
see that I do have persistent storage. Let's
go ahead and right-click on desktop to create
new folder. Name it whatever, then press enter.
You see this folder that I'm moving around
and is now sitting in the center of the desktop.
That is the folder which we have created.
Let me just by the open it and create a new
document which will be named something. If
I open up something and I will write in it.
I know that the image qualities for on this
cell phone so here's what I shall do. I will
do this. The only reason I'm doing this is
so that I can show you that this file will stay
persist through reboot. I can pull the
USB stick out of the machine and it will still
be there, so all I typed in the document is
"AAA..." repeated. Let's go ahead and save
that and close it. Now I am going to reboot the machine
or better yet, let's power off. So I'm powering
off the machine and it's going to shut down
completely. here I pulled the USB stick
out of the machine. The machine is powered
off. You can actually see that there is nothing
plugged into it. There are no cables or anything
of the kind. Plug it back in.
Let's boot the machine. Go ahead and
enter BIOS again. I'm pressing F2
for Dell. Yours might be different. Just reminding
you once again. Any time now, my good man.
So let's go over to legacy. I still can't see USB here, which is perfectly fine. Exit disregarding
changes, ctrl-alt-del. I'll press F12 for boot options.
Okay, so USB storage device, boot from a USB.
Go down to live USB with encrypted
persistence. it will ask me to decrypt all
the drives again, so I won't explain that procedure.
I'll just to go quickly through it.
I am only decrypting the USB drive. I have
the option to decrypt all of my partitions
on this list, but I am not going to do that. That would defeat the purpose of this whole exercise.
SDB3 test. I just put in a
generic key test for reference sake.
I'm going to destroy the contents
of this USB the moment I am done with this
tutorial, so I can use it for something else.
I will use this opportunity to remind everybody that
you can ask in the discussion
section if you would like me to show you how to create a live USB with
some other Linux distribution as well. So
feel free, if you have some other distribution to go
to the discussion section and just say, "Hey!
Can you show us how to create a live
version of this distribution, etc." I will be happy to do it, but please select
some of the major distributions. Don't go out and
for example, select Slackware or something
of a kind because that will be very useful
to you in general. Although it is fantastic,
Slackware is not exactly Linux as the
community says, but it is fairly similar. Anyway,
so it says "whatever." Let's just double-click on
it. I have a file here called Something.
Look! It's filled out with "AAA..." on it.
I have managed to make a persistent live
USB with encrypted storage that is greater
than 4GB. That is only by the size
of your USB. This is fully functional.
It works no problems. It's all functional.
If you have any questions or would like to
request additional content on this subject,
please feel free to go to the discussion section.
One more thing that I would like to remind you
of is that you should not expect that this setup
will work with dual monitors or something
of a kind. I mean you can set it
up to some through a complex procedure or
something of a kind, but generally it won't
work. These things are made just to boot off laptops
and to be used on a laptop. Anyway,
I bid you all farewell. I hope to see you
in the following tutorial!