The skills you learn in this course in ethical hacking and computer security are very valuable skills
that offer tons of ways to make money legally working online helping other people and companies to secure
their computers against exactly what you learn in this course.
Now I'm assuming you can figure out all kinds of legal ways to make money using the skills you learn
in this course and I'm trusting that you will aim your powers for good that you will use the skills
to do good things to help people and to serve other people online.
And if you don't that's up to you right here you've got ways you can legally use these skills to make
money to have job security and to consistently get paid without any fear of anything bad happening to
you.
I work that way today after doing things that did not work that way and where I was afraid of what would
happen of doing things that weren't legal that make money.
And I'm very lucky I'm here today and I can work peacefully.
So I'm showing you that right here the main way you can use these skills to quickly find an opportunity
to make some money out of them and to keep learning them is an up or down come up or Dotcom's formerly
oDesk and Elance.
It is the world the largest online freelancing platform.
That means you can put a profile up and you can use your profile then to get jobs that are exclusively
online that pay by the hour or by project.
And then you earn money by doing work for people in companies that need help with the skills you have.
Now this is the tip of the iceberg what I'm showing here.
I hope what this lecture communicated is that there's a giant potential to use these skills online to
make money in legitimate ways to enhance your career and your resume of what you can do your skills
for the world.
Now all I've done is enter ethical hacking into search term looking at freelancers who are already doing.
What I'm saying is possible for you to do.
And these other profiles I've put it down are at least an hour and build.
So these are people who actually got paid to do this.
No one who's trying or hoping these are people who actually got paid there's hundreds of them alive
right now on up work and you can be one of them using exactly what you learn in this course.
This guy.
Fifty five dollars an hour.
He is charging to do work on the same skills you're learning and time in Hong Kong than Spain.
Thirty four hours here forty four an hour.
Hundreds of hours for this company 15 to 25 an hour.
India twenty five an hour here 11 an hour in Macedonia five dollars an hour for this company $50 an
hour in the U.S. here 16 in Bangladesh 18 an hour in Russia 77 an hour in the U.S. here and thousands
of hours this company's work between three to 25 an hour hundreds of hours 16 dollars an hour.
Here in India 19 hours an hour hundreds of hours worked in the United Kingdom Italy thousands of hours
worked here.
$40 an hour.
What I hope you can see out of this and Pakistan 123 hours of work here $15 an hour top rated.
What I hope you can see out of these profiles I've shown you is that people all over the world are using
the same skills you are learning here to work and make money online for clients that need help with
this.
Now work is just the number one Web site.
For this there's all kinds of other web sites you can find.
You can use Linked In.
You can use fiver or dot com you can find more niche specific sites.
The point is you know there are legal ways to make money helping people with the skills you're learning.
You know all you have to do is keep looking around.
Make an effort and you will find some of those opportunities yourself.
That's why I've shared this with you.
I hope it's useful in getting motivation to learn these skills and I appreciate your time you've spent
here.
I value your feedback on this course at any time.