What does the term hacking mean hacking can mean a lot of different things.
Most generally it means to use something in a way it was not designed to be used.
So when anything's designed it has an intended purpose and intended use in mind that's given by the
designer.
So if I make something for you I have a certain way I think you're going to use it if you use it in
any way besides what I've done in terms of designing it for you to use it that way.
You could call that hacking for this course.
We're focusing mainly on computer security hacking which generally means someone who exploits weaknesses
in a computer system or a computer network.
If you want a lot more information on this you can just go to the Wikipedia dot org article and look
up hacker and hacking on Wikipedia if you want me to read all of the text on this article which fully
explains so many things about hacking including history.
Then just post the discussion and let me know you'd like me to read the whole thing for you.
I trust that you can read if you want to learn more about the exact meaning of the terms and we'll give
you a strong foundation to go into using the rest of this course.
If not Erman will explain more about the specific terms that he thinks are most important for you to
learn going forward.
The bottom line of all of this is that hacking can include a lot of different things.
And what you're given in this course is a set of tools that can make hacking a lot easier.
This often is referred to in some of the people have taken the course of that it as a script kiddie
someone who just uses tools other people made to break into systems the way I look at things it's all
about results.
And if you're trying to learn a skill you need to be able to produce some results out of learning that
skill if you want to use the tools that make it easier to learn how to do things.
Then to me that's my approach.
Usually there's no need to learn things based on a principle when what you need is results.
I hope if you're using this course you can use this for good to help other people secure their systems
against black hat hackers who are using these exact same tools and skills to take things and steal.
Thank you very much for watching this.
And Irma We'll talk a lot more about the terms you see on this page.