What is it you're really here for.
What do you hope to gain out of learning about hacking.
Are you hoping that you can learn these skills and use them to help other people to make a decent life
for yourself of service where you can help other people to protect their systems from Black Hand hackers
and where people will pay you a fee or an hourly rate to help them out to look over their systems to
test their systems and to secure their systems.
Are you looking to use this course to take more for yourself to take more money to take more reputation
to take down someone else who deserves to be taken down.
I've learned the hard way.
I've done both.
And right now I'm doing what I said first.
I've made this course to serve you to be useful for you the information in itself is neutral.
It's not good or bad.
How you use it determines whether it's good or bad.
And I've used hacking in my life to take down people companies games that I thought deserved it.
I've used a lot of the skills in my life to try and take more for myself to get more money to get more
reputation to feel good about myself.
And as long as I use the skills in my life to take from others I was miserable.
I lived in fear of the day when all those others that I'd taken from would come back to judge me and
come back to ask for everything I'd taken.
And then I would have nothing left.
Today I live a life of service that has come out of the misery of misusing so many of the things I learned
and was given in life.
When you use things for everyone's good you can have a wonderful life of peace where you don't have
to be afraid of who's going to knock on your door.
You don't have to be afraid of what people are saying behind your back about what you're doing where
you don't have to be afraid of your friends using your computer and finding out what you're doing on.
I'm grateful today they live a life of transparency where everything I'm doing is out in the open where
everything I'm doing I'm ok sharing with you about I'm ok talking with anyone about who wants to talk
about it today and live a life free of shame where I can use the skills I learned in life for good to
help people.
The choice is up to you.
And I hope what you learn in this course you use to help other people.