How can you get answers to your questions and help with the problems you have learning about ethical
hacking in this course.
I think the most valuable part about this course are not the videos themselves.
I think the community here is where you can get the most help.
There are 33000 plus other students here looking to learn the same things you are doing.
There are hundreds of students here with expert level experience at exactly what you're trying to learn
who have the ability to answer your questions in the course if you post a discussion with your question
the way hundreds of students have done before you you can get an answer every single time you post a
question.
We have people paid here to answer your questions and Erman and I check on the questions in the course
also and other students are looking at the course.
So if you type a title for your discussion and then if you ask the question here you can count on answers
just like the people before you've got within an hour you'll see a quick question here answered within
an hour right away.
Questions down here an hour ago three replies are already questions here.
Two hours ago multi-role replies including screen shots the entire course is like this you can count
on answers to your questions and if you have some really deep technical problems where you would want
to do or if you want to really take it to the intermediate and advanced level try and network with some
other students in the course encourage people to send you a message so that you can chat and meet together
and get to know each other more and then build relationships.
The best examples I've found of that are in my own life.
The most amazing things I've been able to do with anything are when I've collaborated with other people
trying to do the same things I am and collaborated with people that have complimentary skills to mine.
If you bring your skills together and someone else's skills together in the discussion question then
this course then you can get some amazing results.
Some of the lecturers specifically also have discussions related to that lecture.
So if you have questions about that lecture for example or if you have questions about the second lecture
or another lecture and of course you can click on the discussion button here and then you can go over
to the right side up and the right hand corner and you can click on this button and you can see all
of the discussions that relate specifically to this lecture.
If you have problems with things like the course loading or problems with technical issues you can often
download the lecture to get around those problems.
If you have technical problems with working on you to me such as videos playing or payment issues or
anything else with you to me just go to support dot dot com and you can get answers there you can search
Eudemus specific questions like lecture's missing or lecture's not playing right.
And if you have problems you can actually contact you to me by opening a support ticket down here at
the bottom.
All Erman than I do is upload lecture's to this course and then manage the tools to make gifs any of
the tools not working properly.
Any technical problems only you and me can solve Erman and I cannot solve them.
So thank you very much for getting this far into the course are ready Armand and I are consistently
working to make this the best course possible for you and we'd love to know if you liked the course.
If you have any ideas for what we can add to it also.
Thank you.