One of the awesome things you get out
of taking this course
is a certificate
you can display
online when you've completed.
On LinkedIn you can add this
certificate to your profile
to build your online resume,
and enhance
your ability to get a job
using the skills you
have learned in this course.
You can add the certificate once
you've got it.
If you scroll down on editing
your profile,
you can then click on adding
a certificate,
and you can then put everything in
that you get from the certificate,
here.
Where do you get the certificate?
You have a bar on the top
of your course,
Now, since I am the instructor, it
doesn't show on this course.
You will have a bar up here,
that shows you how close
to finishing the course you are,
how many lectures you've completed
on the course,
so when you go through each lecture,
this bar will continue to fill up
and then there's a little trophy
at the end of it.
Once you've filled the bar and
completed every lecture in the course
you get a trophy.
Once you clicked on the trophy,
Udemy will give you your certificate.
It will give you a certificate
you can print out
and it will also give you
a link online
that you can use to fill in this
information on LinkedIn
and if any employer
or
web
platform like Upwork ask
for your certificate link,
you can give that exact link,
which will show proof that you've
completed the course on Udemy,
and will give you somehting tangible
to show that you've gotten
out of this course.
Now, if you want a shortcut,
which you're on a hacking course
it's certainly possible, you might
want a shortcut.
On the trophy is based on clicking the
lectures.
Well, if you click on a lecture,
all you have to do is click on
this little
check button down here,
to hit mark as completed. So you hit
"Mark as completed."
And then
it registers that you've completed
the lecture.
So, theoretically,
you can just go through and hit mark
as completed on every single lecture
and then get your certificate that
way.
Now, you might not learn anything but
that's up to you.
You can still get your certificate
even without watching any
lectures in the course.
This is helpful
in case you go to watch
a beginning of a lecture
and you decide:
"Ok, I don't need to watch
the whole thing."
You can mark it as completed
and move on.
Or if you watch say, like this
it has a little green circle on it
that means it's not completed.
You can see these lectures
are completed.
I've watched the entire
lecture on both of these.
And what you ultimately need are green
check marks
on every lecture on the course.
to get your trophy.
Or if you watched part of a lecture
and it didn't register as completed,
You can just go back, bring that
lecture up
and hit completed right away,
So that then you can bring up your
certificate.
I appreciate you watching this,
and hope this is useful for you
in showing off what you've
learned
in this course, in a tangible way
that other people can see.