This Course offers you the chance to go from a beginner who's never used anything in this course all
the way to advanced I would say advanced as someone who is employable who can proficiently work with
all the tools in this course and who can earn a good salary in a job or working online.
In using what you see in these tools and can successfully use the things for themselves obviously watching
25 hours of video in this course is not going to take you to the advanced level by itself.
This course gives you a strong foundation upon which you can use the motivation from this course that
you've enjoyed learning with it to build on that foundation into advanced this course gives you enough
to become proficient.
I've noticed it takes me around 20 hours of using something of taking a course of interacting and going
hands on to get proficient.
That means you can feel reasonably comfortable using the tools you can feel reasonably comfortable doing
the things you see in this course.
That's the foundation on which you can build into advanced.
So this course will not take you into being an expert by itself.
You have to do the work along with this course and I've learned this I'm teaching 43 courses I'm new
to me now.
Almost all of which I've learned in the last four years and I've partnered up as you can see on this
course with Erman I've partnered up with people who are much better than I am at the subject that we're
teaching here.
The idea is that if you partner up with people who are better than you you learn rapidly all the subjects
that I've been able to learn quickly.
I've learned from other people who were ahead of me.
So when you take this course you're learning from people who are ahead of where you're at.
And then when you connect with students and this course when you go in the discussions and you see the
other people learning with you the other people posting things in here with you and you take the time
you can click on their profile and view their profile and send them a message.
You can connect with other students in this course and learn together and collaborate and then you can
share the energy of collaborating together.
You can talk you can get to know people and that's how you can go to advanced going to advance takes
a lot of time and energy and effort and to get to advanced usually need to love what you're doing.
And any subject I've been advanced I've loved what I'm doing enough to do it a little bit every day.
The courses I'm teaching by myself that go to an advanced level in the course just like this one goes
to an advanced level here with me and Erman these courses are founded on thousands of hours of experience.
Erman has a ridiculous amount of time that he's put into learning and using the subjects he's teaching
here with you.
All you have to do is put the time and energy into learning and using these subjects yourself and you
will get to advanced.
To summarize I hope this course gives you motivation to see if you want to get too advanced.
And if you're willing to put the same amount of time and effort into learning ethical hacking that Ermin
has put into learning ethical hacking then you will get the same skills at the same level that Erman
is teaching the course.
And thank you very much for watching this.
And I hope this gives you a clear direction as to how you can use this course to go from beginner to
advanced.