Thank you very much for finishing this course.
Awesome work getting all the way through it or skipping the bottom to find the bonus either way.
Thank you for making it to the very last video on the course.
This video is going to show you how to get every other course that Ermine's teaching for 50 percent
off and it will show you how to get free coupons to any course I'm teaching and it will recommend some
courses you might want to do next.
So this is my website.
Jerry Banfield dot com slash courses.
I'm grateful that I'm teaching with Erman because Erman just wants to teach.
He doesn't want to fool around with having to do marketing spend thousand dollars advertising courses
and figure out a way to do it.
My specialty is Internet marketing online advertising so Armon and I have teamed up.
All he does is make the courses and my primary role is to advertise them and sell them.
That's why you're here with me now and explain the value of them to you.
So all the courses you can find Ermine's profile in the course you can always just search on you to
me for Erman Kalponik and click on Ermin chronic there.
Now you can see the courses Erman is currently teaching now some of these.
By the time you watch this there may be more.
This is the first course we made together.
If you want to learn about Wireshark and tracking network traffic this may be really helpful for you.
That complete hacking course you're enrolled in this.
Now the Red Hat Linux and sent OS if you want to continue to enhance your Linux skills and maybe take
the Linux Red Hat certified system administrators Zahm this might be a great course to take.
Next for hacking if you want to have your own functional key logger.
This seems to be one of the favorite courses people take.
Next is it shows you exactly how to build an advanced key logger using C++.
It currently is undetectable by any anti-virus software and Ermine's shows you how to build it from
start to finish.
If you don't know C++ at all you might want to take this learn and understand C++ course first and then
take the advanced key logger course after that so that you'll be more comfortable in C++ to build the
key logger then.
This is a free course if you're in the hacking course.
This just has the first couple of hours for free so if you're already in the hacking course there's
no need to take this one.
If you want to master the Linux command line and adventure bash programming then this bash programming
course with Erman might be a good course to take.
Next you can see the prices I'm here and you can get 50 percent off all of these on my website so Ermine's
courses are currently right in the middle straight down so the hacking.
Wireshark.
BASH key logger understands C++.
Redhat straight down in the middle to get these all you do then you just click on the coupon and it
opens up a page with the coupon already applied.
So to do this I have to go private browser because I'm already browsing this now so this is what it
look like.
You can see it with the coupon already applied and then you just click on any other link.
For example if I go back here grab one to the wireshark course and then come back over and tap this
in.
Then you put that in.
You can see that it's 50 percent off that way.
So any of these links will get you 50 percent off to Ermine's courses.
Now I have 60 plus courses I'm new to me right now I'm teaching I'm jury BANFIELD So you go find my
profile.
You can see how many courses I'm teaching and you can get half off of any of those courses.
Also this page when you combine the skills you learned with Ermin with the skills you learn with me
you can have some fantastic capabilities online.
I teach a lot of online advertising and marketing courses.
I have a how to teach on you to make course just like I'm doing here with you now.
I have a freelancing course which could really help you if you want to apply the skills that you have
with ethical hacking freelancing and making money online.
If you want to have a happy fully productive life.
My 10 daily goals course and four hour work day course might be great for that.
You can learn about Bitcoin.
I would think there's a great opportunity to use bitcoin in the world of ethical hacking especially
you might enjoy this bitcoin course I'm teaching with the top Bitcoin instructor Anyuta me.
I have five courses help the courses and science courses digital market getting a buntu Linux course
you might enjoy an exam or in course of productivity video production.
Google Analytics startup endless courses that I've both made videos in and am teaching with other people
I've tried to pair up with instructors who are similar to me so you can see Ermine's teaching style
and my teaching style as a big overlap so then all the courses I'm teaching it tends to work the same
way.
So you can check out.
I even have a free course with over 200 videos and a daily inspirational course.
People seem to really like this one.
Designing and building your own computer.
Another great thing you can do especially if you want to do your ethical hacking and a more effective
level.
So you can get 50 percent off of all of these courses on my website.
Now I even have a sweet free offer here so if you scroll down on the very bottom of my web site you'll
notice I have offered to get free at you to me course coupon every week via e-mail this is something
new I've just started.
So if you put your name and e-mail in here and subscribe I will send you a free coupon every single
week to one of my you do me courses So sometimes they'll be with Erman most of the time they won't be
because I have so many courses already and then I can see from what we were teaching before he has six
or seven courses with me so over 52 weeks most of the courses will be what you see on this page.
And then I also if you are wanting to learn to build a business online like I have I have a resources
page here on the top of my web site.
It shows everything I use to run my business my from my hosting my theme of it shows all the things
I use to film in my studio.
It shows how I manage and keep track of my finances.
It's show for my business.
It shows my home office set up and it shows then other places I even host my courses I have a blog on
my website and Erman.
Also I started a log on his YouTube channel if you just Google Armond Kirkpatrick YouTube you can find
Ermine's YouTube channel and he's starting a V log on there that then gives you the chance to keep up
with Erman.
So if you want to get to that on my profile you can click on my YouTube channel.
It'll take you over to my YouTube channel and then on the hacking video I've done with Erman which you
might have seen already and I'll have Erman listed as a collaborator on here.
And this takes you over Ermine's channel you can see this is his newest update on his feet log.
And then if you subscribe to Erman like you can see I'm subscribed to Erman now I've subscribed to Erman
here so I get his video updates also.
So if you you can use all these links on my profile to find these things for yourself.
So my web site is full of things you might find helpful free you to me of course coupon every single
week down here.
I even have a page where I have books that I've written here and a bunch to Linux book you might like.
And then you can even schedule a call with me if you want to talk with me about something.
This is the way if you want to get a hold of me and actually get me to pay attention to something called
the way to do it so I hope is sharing all this with you is useful if you want more ethical hacking courses
even.
I've got a page on my Gerri Banfield dot com slash courses.
It even has other ethical hacking courses you might enjoy.
Based on the ones I'm teaching are ready survie click ethical hacking course coupons on my web site.
Gerri Banfield dot com slash hacking you'll see Ermine's courses here and then you'll see some other
ones you might enjoy Ticken Tinu your ethical hacking.
So that's on Jerry Bamfield dot com slash hacking.
Thank you very much for finishing this course up.
I hope to see you again wherever it is.
Next on another course my YouTube channel website email list.
Thank you.
And I hope you have a great day.