Hello everybody and welcome to this
tutorial.
Here, I'm just gonna continue from where I left off in the previous one.
If you have not seen the previous tutorial, I
strongly urge you to do so
as the two are closely interrelated, so to say.
Anyway, previously we discussed some of these things
such as DoS, RAT, fishing and so on and so forth.
But here, I wanna go a step further
and tell you about SQL injections, VPNs,
proxies, Tor, VPS, key loggers
and so on and so forth.
You will see how all these things will
play a role later on
throughout the course.
But for the time being
you have SQL injections, which are simply passing SQL queries to HTTP requests.
If they are not properly formatted by the PHP code on the server side
this can present a serious problem
and this is always one of the primary
considerations
of all the web developers out there.
Later on I will demonstrate how you can use these
formulate them
and there is a large amount of websites that are vulnerable out there
primarily because the frameworks on which they're based
are vulnerable as well.
Next up, you have Virtual Private Networks
so VPNs
These are ways of anonymizing yourselves.
Basically, if you have a VPN provider somewhere
and if you want you anonymize yourself
you will route all their traffic through this VPN provider
and all the traffic between you and the VPN provider will be heavily encrypted.
So any other server out there
if it is receiving requests from you
it is actually receiving them from VPN.
There is no real way of detecting you or fighting your physical location
unless the VPN provider actually gives it up.
which doesn't really happen if you pick the right one.
Down below you have proxies.
Now proxies are a less reliable way of staying anonymous
but you should always make it your common practice to use Socks5 proxies.
I will explain what these are
I will introduce them when we do proxy chains
and when I explain to you how you can
actually stay anonymous
while conducting these sort of activities.
You will realize that you can route your connection through several proxies
but very soon you will see as well, that doesn't always work.
In the movies or something like that you see people going through 10
or 20 different proxies.
In reality that would be very VERY difficult to implement
primarily because of internet speeds
because of the available bandwidth.
Most of the free proxies out there are not very fast
and routing your connection through several of them
will make it very difficult for you to do anything in a reasonable amount of time.
There are, of course, paid proxies
but when you pay a proxy, you leave digital footprints somewhere
so you can be traced.
Down below, you have Tor.
Now Tor is absolutely free open source
and it's much faster than proxies.
It's not faster than VPNs, but it is faster than proxies.
It gives you the ability to torify your applications
which in essence, means simply routing
traffic through certain routes
and using certain routers on the Internet to
actually
not just routers, but using certain devices
on the Internet for your packets
for your connection to go through.
It can be slow from time to time.
It is not a 100% guarantee
but you will be anonymous to a very large extent
if you are using Tor.
There are ways of detecting you
but they are HIGHLY unlikely to happen Nike night
Like 99.99% of time, you will be almost 100% anonymous
which is a very good way of functioning.
Also, you have the Tor browser
which allows you to access dark web, or hidden web
however you wish to call it.
Basically, those are ".onion" websites
and they are not indexed by any other search engines out there
and they cannot be accessed by a regular internet route...
from the regular internet browsing perspective.
You cannot...I mean if you open up Firefox
and if you had your internet connection
and if you don't have your internet connection configured in a proper way
to connect it to a network, or something of a kind
you will not be able to access any of the hidden webs, dark webs, website services
and so on and so forth.
Now I will also show you how to access dark web and how to use it
as it has a vast amount of resources that are at your disposal
most of them free
some of them paid, and so on and so forth.
Down below, you have VPS.
These are Virtual Private Servers.
It is a method of...
it is a security...
it can viewed as a security layer.
For example, if you have an Apache server
running on your physical machine
you can have a virtual machine within
that physical machine
which will serve as an SQL Server for that Apache server.
This is done so that the SQL server cannot be accessed from outside
and that you don't have an SQL port open
on your physical machine.
So only devices
only programs
and users from that particular machine
will be able to access to virtual machine where the SQL Server is.
A bit of back and forth action here.
It might sound unclear or something like that
but I don't want you to worry about it now.
When I show the  examples when you get into it
you will understand it.
I guarantee it to you.
So no problems there.
Here I'm just introducing you to the terminology
and giving you an idea of what's to come.
Excellent
So we also have "Key Loggers"
which are tools that are used to steal credentials
and not only credentials
but also used to extract information.
If you manage to deploy a key logger on a machine
you can configure it to send
to record all keystrokes and send them to a mail address
to an FTP server.
Today, key loggers are advanced to the extent
that they have
they have like a hundred options or so
configurable to the fullest of extents
and you can do pretty much whatever you want with them
I mean, they have their basic functionalities
the basic functionalities are still there
to record the keystrokes
but not only do they record keystrokes
for example
they can extract existing information as well.
You can configure their behavior
how is the stealth level of the key logger?
How will it hide?
Where will it go?
Where will it be installed?
What sort of information do you want to extract?
Do you want monitor particular folders for activity
and you want to record it?
You can configure them take screenshots.
You can configure them to use the camera on the device
on which you had deployed a key logger to take a picture every five minutes
or something like that
That wouldn't be the of brightest ideas
because obviously somebody would that you are taking a picture
but those are just examples of what you
can do with them
and later on we will actually download the genuine keylogger
Install it
Deploy it
and show methods of deployment and how you can configure it as well
although you should be very careful from where you download your tools
such as key loggers, remote demonstration tools, rootkits
and so on and so forth.
Primarily because you never ever want to download
an uncompiled binary file that is not open source
because you have no way of knowing what's in it
and you absolutely NEVER want to run it on your computer
You might get what you want
you know, a key logger or something of a kind
but your computer might get infected with exactly the same key logger
that you planned to deploy somewhere
or with exactly the same wrath that you intended to deploy somewhere.
So that's a very bright idea.
You should use verified sources of such tools.
I will show a few of them later on
as I go over to the internet and download them
but I'm just making it very clear here
that you should be very careful with these things
and one of the full proof methods of doing this
is actually configuring a virtual machine
and doing this sort of activity on that virtual machine.
So even if you get infected or something of a kind
it doesn't matter.
It's a virtual machine.
You can reinstall it anytime you want.
Very fast
Pretty much no information will be lost there.
More importantly, the primary file system on your main physical machine
will not be accessed from the virtual machine
Anyway, down below you have the terminal
So terminal is basically an interface for you
that allows you to control your operating system.
Now, Linux terminal is VERY powerful.
We will be using it extensively.
You will need to familiarize yourselves with it.
I will familiarize you with it.
I will teach how to use it.
To some people, it might seem a bit difficult
or a bit tricky at first sight.
You know, there are a lot of commands to type in --
How to memorize them all
What to use where, and so on and so forth
but believe me, there is a certain logic to it
and once you figure it out, everything
just flies.
I know by heart about 30% of possible commands out there.
regarding Linux terminals
and the rest I simply figure out with dash H or dash dash help.
The system pretty much tells you everything you need to know.
It helps you out to a great extent
and you are able to figure out a lot of
things
from just understanding the basic logic
of how it works
and so on.
Now, there will always of course be arguments
I don't know, maybe people saying "Why would you use terminals?"
"Why won't you just use GUI tools or something like that?"
The simple answer is because they are not as nearly as powerful
as the terminal tools are.
Plus, terminal tools have far less dependencies
and most the hacking tools are basically designed for the terminals.
They're not...they don't have GUIs.
A lot of do have them these days
but I might go over them briefly at a certain point of time
because it is not...
the GUI interfaces are not that relevant
When you figure out how to do it in the terminal
you will automatically, by default
know how to do it with the Graphical
User Interface
for that particular program.
Anyway, down below you have firewalls.
Now, firewall in Linux is configured through IP table commands
You keep on passing arguments and configuring these firewalls
and this is one of the main reasons
why you should not be using any distribution of windows
for this particular tutorial --
to follow this tutorial.
You will need to install
as I said previously
will need to install either a Linux virtual machine or create a duel boot
or something of a kind.
I will, of course, show how to do this and demonstrate it in great detail what are the main
but one of the main reasons --
the firewalls are one of the main reasons
why we can't use windows for these sort of purposes.
Linux firewall is open source
and it has a ridiculous amount of options
a ridiculous amount.
Enough getting here...
You can do with it pretty much whatever you want.
You can configure.
You can close and open ports.
Forward connections via ports or via IP addresses.
You can close...
you can just forbid certain protocols on certain ports
or forbid certain protocols for certain IP addresses.
Do all manner of forwarding and redirection
and so on and so forth.
This all available for free with a Linux
firewall
While in Windows, you will have some of these options
but most of them you won't unless you, for example
buy a certain package or something like that
which is not something that we really want to do here.
We want to keep this budget-friendly
and we want to have a powerful firewall
which can do pretty much whatever we want it to do.
Now, there will be two ways of configuring this firewall
and if you are afraid of messing it up, don't worry about it
because most configurations that we will do will be short-lived configurations
so to say
primarily because all the configurations made to the firewall
from iptables command
unless specified otherwise
will be temporary, and they will hold until the next system reset.
There is a way to circumvent this, of course
and to configure the firewall rules in the configuration file directly
and thereby making the changes permanent
which is also one of the ways of doing  it
but I don't generally prefer it
I prefer it to have a script somewhere which you can run at anytime
and it will configure firewall by default.
This is primarily because you want to
have your tools set in a USB stick
or somewhere in the line
or something of a kind.
and you have these quick scripts, which you generate
and then they perform these tasks for
you in an automated fashion.
It's really simple.
I will show you how to make these scripts.
You don't need...
You do not necessarily need some advanced programming knowledge
or anything of a kind.
Basically what these scripts are
are lists of Linux terminal commands
which we will do anyway.
So basically, the script would consist out of a list of those commands
then you just change the mod of the script to be an executable file
run it
and all those commands are past the system
and those tasks are finished in an automated fashion, by default.
Anyway, one of the final things that I wish to address here
are "Reverse-shells"
There are hundreds, if not thousands of reverse-shells out there
that you can use.
I will pick a few that we will use, depending on the framework
depending on the environment, of course, that we want to infect.
But in essence, what reverse-shells are
as the name itself says
you have a program, which you infect in another device
and then that program opens up a reverse connection from that device
back to you.
So you can keep on passing commands.
You can keep on controlling the system
even though you are nowhere near it. there are
different types of course today
There are different types, of course, today with routers
and so on and so forth.
With such firewalls, you need to do a lot of extra configuration
and there are problems that need to be solved and addressed.
You'll see how when you're trying to break into a single computer
sometimes you need to break into the
router first.
Usually you need to break into the router first
unless you're performing these fishing sort of attacks
or there's a web server, or something of a kind, running in the background
But attacking a private device --
private computer, which is usually what
people do
as preludes to bigger hacks
because they want to extract some sort of information
or something of a kind
from let's say, a company's employee that's a network administrator
or somebody like that.
They will...
One of the basic factors would be to attack a home router
change the DNS settings there
and try to steal credentials in such a way
or put the computer in the DMZ of the router
demilitarized zone
so that the router is no longer effective for the device.
Rather instead, it just forwards all traffic to that device regardless
So that can be...
Those are some of the types of attacks you can do
but reverse-shells will depend on the choice of the environment
that you are trying to infect
and will depend on the choice of your attack route, as well.
In any case, I hope that you got some basic introduction to these terms
and I again repeat, if you didn't figure it out all immediately
don't worry about it.
We will do all of this in great details with a lot of examples
and you will understand it.
It is not complicated.
Do not allow fear to dissuade or stop you.
Just keep on going in spite of it
and if you can just stick in to the end of this course
I guarantee it to you, you will understand it
with just a bit a focus and a bit of curiosity
you will be able to obtain the necessary skills needed
in order to become a pen tester or an ethical hacker.
I bid you all farewell and I hope to see you in the next tutorial.