Hello everybody and welcome to part two of
this tutorial. Let's go ahead and save the
file. Press control-O to output the file.
It says file filename to write. You can actually
modify it here. You can type in some letters
or whatever you want to change the name here.
You can even change the extension if you want.
There is no need for the time being. I'm just
going to go ahead and save it as "test." Just
press enter. There you go. It says, "wrote
one line. Hit control-X to exit. There we
go. Clear the screen. Now, I'm going to use
cat command to get a listing of this particular
file, which is far more reasonable than the
previous one, which you couldn't read. The
command, by the way, was functioning properly
but it was mostly a binary file. Therefore
I mean, it gave you listing but you couldn't
really read anything from it. So just go ahead
and type in cat test and there we go. It says,
"some random text goes here." That is the
text that we have typed into the test file
and you can cat it like this. These things
are very good, especially with files that
you want to make sure not to change them in
any way, you don't want to make any accidental
changes or anything of the kind and you want
to quickly see what is located within that
file. There is another way of doing this.
Basically, it's "ls." Let's go ahead and get
over to "cd etc/apt/." "Ls." We have plenty
of files to work with. Let's take sources.list
as an example here. So if I do "cat sources.list"
I'm going to get everything that is within
that file as before. It is listed in my terminal,
it's here to stay. It's not going anywhere.
There is another command which I could use.
Just go ahead and clear the screen. It is
called "less." If I type, "less sources.list"
I will be prompted with a new tab where I
can actually view things here. Not a new terminal
tab, but a new workspace within the within
the terminal itself. When I press Q I exit
and nothing will be displayed here. So very
nice in terms of being neat, organized and
so on and so forth. So less and cat are very
nice things. You can use, for example, "cat
sources.list" and the command that I have
previously mentioned is "grep." "Grep" means
you pull something, grep something from somewhere
else. Here's what I mean by it. Type in "cat
sources.list" and you type in a pipe. This
symbol here. It's called a pipe which basically
states whatever the output of this is pipe
it to whatever command comes here. So, I'm
just going to type in "grep" and let's say
I want to type in, "src." Press enter. Excellent.
So it will only print lines that have "src"
in them. Linux is case-sensitive. When you
are grepping, it's going to check whether
it's lowercase or not. You can give it an
ignore case. You can type this, "-i" to ignore
the case. This time, you're going to get the
same output because there are no different
things within this file. You get the general
idea. So this is how you would use "cat" with
grep to pull things out of a file. Very important.
This is a huge part of the Linux terminal--
filtering through text files. Primarily because
we are going to be doing large network scans
and we will want to create files from which
we will be able to pool useful information.
We will later in turn pass this information
to other tools to do something with. Anyway,
just go ahead and clear to screen for the
time being. You also have "echo." Type "echo
"I AM ALIVE"." It will echo these words it
literally is an echo. You type something into
it and it echoes them here. Let's go back
to the home directory, get a listing and use
exactly the same command echo live. By the
way, you can scroll through previous commands
by using arrow key. So using the up arrow
key or the down arrow key, you can scroll
back through previous commands and you don't
need to retype them. So I am alive. I'm going
to insert this. I will use a ">" and type
in "test." This will echo "I AM ALIVE" into
test. It has replaced the contents of the
test, which was "some random text goes here"
into, "I AM ALIVE." Very nice command to have.
You can change variable names, variable values
with echo and so on and so forth. We will
use this a bit more as we progress through
the course. I don't really want to get in-depth
here. Primarily because later on when we have
clear examples that directly relate to what
we are doing, which is basically testing,
then you will see more advanced usage of pretty
much all of these commands-- especially grep.
You have "touch."Touch" is a quick way to
create files. So, for example, I can type,
"touch file1 file2 file3." Press enter, "ls."
You see, it immediately created three files.
That is a very quick method to create any
amount of files. You can specify a folder.
You can create this file in home, this one
in var, this one in varlog, and so on and
so forth. Down below, you have "mkdir." Type
in, "mkdir" and it makes a directory. So you
are making some sort of a directory. Let's
say this the name of this directory will be
"placeToBe." If I hit "ls." There we go. It
states that is the does that this file is
actually a directory, which is PlaceToBe.
I can even navigate to it and say, "PlaceToBe
ls." There is nothing in it but you get the
idea. You can make directories in such a fashion.
Now, if I type "chown" it allows you to change
the ownership of a particular file. Since
we only have a single user here, which is
root, there isn't really any point in doing
so. If we create some of the new users we
could do that. However, we don't need them.
I'll just show you how this would work. For
example, if the owner of the file was not
root and you want to change it to root, do
the following. Type, "chown," then you would
type the username ":" and the user group.
The user group and the username are usually
the same on your home PC, unless you have
some bigger servers or something like that.
Then just specify the name of the file. You
can type "test." There it will effectively
change the ownership of file test to the username
root, who is from the user group root. If
I do "ls la" it states who the owners are
and which groups actually owned the files
as well. Clear the screen. There is another
more used command. It's called "chmod." This
command allows you to change file permissions.
This is something that you will need to use
on daily basis and quite often. Primarily
because, you see if I have an executive file
in Linux, for example. Let's just go ahead
and type in, "echo hello." I want to that
to test and I want to test to test.sh. "Sh"
is basically an executable one, that's a bash
script for Linux that in such a way you can
automate tasks. We will deal with it in greater
depth as we proceed through the tutorial.
You will need to be acquainted with bash scripting
definitely. Bash scripting is very similar
to the terminal itself, so pretty much all
the commands used in the terminal, can be
used by scripting as well. You basically just
combine a bunch of them in a file. Now, I
want this to be my executable, but you see
the way to to start executables is "./" as
stated previously that's the command to start
any executable. If I type in test, and press
that, it doesn't give me a list of possibilities.
Now, surely test.sh is an executable, but
no you see, it doesn't have a permission to
be an executable file. See here the difference,
take a look at this file and take a look at
this file. This one is green, this one is
not. Now look at their permissions. So you
see, it has a markation that is executable
for all groups, users, etc., while this one
up here does not have such permissions. You
need to change that. What you do to change
it is, "chmod." You would type in, "+x." If
you want the file to be writable you type,
"+w," if you want it to be executable "+x,"
if you want to be able to read the file, "+r,"
very simple. There is also a way of doing
this with numbers. You can type in, "755."
Don't try remembering all those modes. Whatever
you need go on the internet and check. It
can be quite complicated, but these three
you need to know: +x, +r, and +w. Also 777,
which is a global mode. This is the mode which
is not recommended for actual usage, but you
use "chmode" to actually test or troubleshoot
things. For example, if you want to be absolutely
sure that certain actions are not being prevented
due to file permissions, you change the mode
of those files to 777, which is the global
mode that anybody can do anything with the
file. If you still have an error message you
know that it is absolutely not related to
anything in regards to permissions. So, those
four things to do need to know. You can just
go ahead and type, "chmod +x test.sh," press
enter. If I do "ls la" once again, you will
see that test.sh is now executable. Let me
just run it and there you go. If I run this
it's going to echo "hello" on my terminal
screen. There's a bit more to go. Not much
more left. There is just one more command
that I would really like show you. This can
be a very dangerous command. Indeed, it can
mess you up in ways you can't begin to imagine
yet. that is the command "rm." "Rm" is basically
remove. Once you remove things with this command,
it's next to impossible to recover pretty
much anything. So, if I type in, "rm test.sh,"
it's going to remove it. It's no longer going
to be there. If I go ahead and navigate over
to PlaceToBe and I "touch test" to make a
new file there. If I go ahead and say "RM
PlaceToBe." It will say "rm cannot remove
place to be because it is a directory." This
is a failsafe of the rm. So, you wouldn't
delete a full directory because you will be
able to recover it, and that would be really
bad. What you can do is type in, "rm -f PlaceToBe."
Cannot remove directory. Okay, no problems.
Sometimes you get stuck. I'm deliberately
going to leave this part in the tutorial.
I'll just troubleshoot it. So you type in,
"--help." Here you have recursive remove directories
and their contents recursively. So, that's
a very nice option. So, let's just go ahead
and do that because this will go into the
folder and remove everything within the folder
and the folder itself, hopefully. So, just
go ahead and type in, "rm -r PlaceToBe," press
enter. There you go. It has deleted it. There
we go, it is no longer there. The "-f" that
I have used is force. It will not ask you
any questions. It will delete the folder or
file, which can be also very dangerous. When
you're using "rm," you always want to be asked
questions. In any case, as I said, I deliberately
left his to show you that even if you get
stuck worry about it. I get stuck all the
time. If you don't know what to type in, what
argument to pass, just type in "--help." Take
a look at what you can actually type, read
a little bit and then use the options. Try
it out, sometimes it will work, sometimes
it won't. More often than not, you will be
able to figure it out from the help menu.
If you can't figure it out from help menu,
just typed in "man rm" and you can read pretty
much everything there is to know about this
command here. If you really can't perform
the task, if you can find anything useful
here, forums are your next best bet. Trust
me you will succeed in doing it. In any case,
this was a brief introduction some of the
basic commands that we will use. Please make
sure that you know what each one of these
commands does, at least basic functions. Later
on we will get in-depth, do more advanced
stuff and use more advanced commands by combining
them, and so on. In any case, I bid you all
farewell. I hope to see you in the next tutorial.